Jeremy L. Shepherd

Full Stack Developer

Xenia, Ohio

937.475.2375

github.com/jeremylshepherd jeremylshepherd.github.io

About Me

How I got into coding

In 2014, I wanted to have a website to showcase my photography. I started with WordPress templates but never found one that spoke to me. I decided to learn enough coding to build my own webpage. Eventually, I landed on Codecademy's site. I took one class, then two, then three... until I had taken nearly every course on the site. I was hooked and have been since. I have expanded my knowledge and built several projects. I enjoy the challenge of solving problems with code.

Skills Summary

- React
- React Native
- Angular
- NodeJS

- ExpressJS
- MongoDB/SQL
- Ruby-on-Rails
- Git

Current Project

Building a React-Native Client to interface with my citation tracking application

Professional Experience

2003-Present Good Samaritan Hospital Dayton, OH

Campus Police Officer (Sergeant)

- Promoted to Sergeant in 2008
- Managed a small team of professionals
- Built the citation tracking application now used by the department.

2000–2005 Kroger Xenia, OH

Loss Prevention Agent

Self scheduled and self managed

1999–2006 Cedarville Police Dept. Cedarville, OH

Police Officer

Functioned with limited direct supervision in a field that demands a high level of accountability

1999–2000 Wilberforce Univ. Police Dept. Wilberforce, OH

Campus Police Officer

• Functioned with limited direct supervision in a field that demands a high level of accountability

Education

- Senior, BCJ Program (Ohio University, Inactive)
- AAS Criminal Justice (Sinclair Community College
- Free Code Camp Completed Front-End, Data Visualization, and Back-end Certifications.